<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Point Estimates</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Point Estimates</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Context is King</title>
      <link>/post/2022-01-04-context-is-king/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-01-04-context-is-king/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;{{&lt; blogdown/postref &gt;}}index.en_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;TOC&#34;&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Casual Causality, or a Study of Studies</title>
      <link>/post/2021-12-16-casual-causality-or-a-study-of-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-12-16-casual-causality-or-a-study-of-studies/</guid>
      <description>One of the most interesting questions we can ask is “does x cause y?”. If we know what causes something, we can avoid it (we know that fire ignites gas, so we don’t light a candle in a room filled with propane) or pursue it (we know that diet and exercise lead to better health outcomes, so we grudgingly go with it). You may never run a test like this yourself, but since they’re so prevalent it’s helpful to understand how they work and what makes a test good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heil Hydra? What are the odds they&#39;re in charge?</title>
      <link>/post/2021-11-29-heil-hydra-what-are-the-odds-they-re-in-charge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-11-29-heil-hydra-what-are-the-odds-they-re-in-charge/</guid>
      <description>You’ve just received word from a friend that Hydra has secretly taken over the government for its own nefarious reasons. There’s only one source for this info, though, and the evidence they cite is primarily circumstantial. However; the narrative provided would explain a lot of things. How can we go about sorting this out?
Firstly, let’s not that this exercise can’t provide a definitive answer to whether or not Hydra has in fact taken root.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pitching Wins Playoffs, Unless it Doesn&#39;t.</title>
      <link>/post/2021-11-22-pitching-wins-unless-it-doesn-t/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-11-22-pitching-wins-unless-it-doesn-t/</guid>
      <description>Every year, we hear that pitching wins the MLB postseason. This is often said by ex-pitchers so we expect some bias, but even so there’s some merit. After all, teams get to take advantage of the travel schedule to go from five starters to four, putting their worst starter in the bullpen where he’ll either ride the bench or be used in shorter, more effective spurts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sample Size and Percentages: What to Expect</title>
      <link>/post/2021-11-15-sample-size/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-11-15-sample-size/</guid>
      <description>People are really good at comparing numbers. If you have 1,000 apples and I have 10, you can tell me pretty quickly that you have 990 more apples than I do. You can also put that into some context - we know intuitively that that’s a lot of apples - so it’s helpful as well.
Percentages are numbers as well, so they should be easy to measure as well.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
